what misconceptions about hormone
optimization do you encounter most often
and how do you address
them I think the biggest misconception
that we all get is that testosterone is
going to cause strokes and heart attacks
and cancer those are probably the top
three that I hear from people coming in
whether it be from the General Media the
public or from other Physicians that
that are that are refusing treatment and
then these guys are coming in seeking
treatment um my first answer to anyone
that says testosterone is going to cause
a heart attack a stroke cancer Etc is I
say whoever made that claim needs to
prove their claim you're going to make a
claim the burden of proof is on you I
don't need to prove that it doesn't I
you you need to prove that it does right
because you're the one that that's
claiming that a new event is going to
occur if you use this
input and they can't they cannot prove
it all I ever get is well my doctor's
been doing this for 30 years that's
great so he's been wrong for 30 years
that tells me nothing a lot of people
have been doing a lot of things for a
very long time it doesn't mean that they
are correct heck I've been wrong on a
lot of things in life the minute I am
proven wrong I change my tune I
apologize I learn and I develop a new
path that is what makes human beings so
spectacular is we can adapt we can
accept and we can we can learn the right
thing sticking to
erroneous information for your ego is
not going to help your ego in a long run
and it's certainly not going to help
your patience so rather than just
opening up a debate and trying to Stand
My Ground and prove them wrong I just
ask them to prove it and they never can
they never can and if anybody wants to
have any ammunition in their back pocket
regarding cardiovascular health and
testosterone in June of
2023 the largest study ever conducted
with human beings and
testosterone specifically for
cardiovascular health was conducted and
published and it is called the Traverse
trial you can look it up um and it is
fairly lengthy and it is fairly
conclusive and it clearly shows that men
with low testosterone levels are at a
far greater risk for all arterior
scerotic cardiovascular disease than men
with optimal
levels uh and that is some of the most
extensive and latest research that we
have available so anyone harping studies
from the 70s ' 80s 90s that is purely
correlative and
inconclusive should refer to the newer
and more conclusive studies and uh and
stop you know beating the desk on
nonsense but that is probably the
biggest misconception